Hello everyone and welcome back
to English Pot. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today
we're talking about buying clothes.
That's right we're gonna
go and get some clothes
but on this occasion
we are going to get a suit
and we're gonna have
it made especially for us.
So before we get started
why don't we take a look
at one keyword that we have in
vocabulary preview. Very cabaret preview.
Okay this word makes
me think of things that
are very rich and
soft. It's a fabric right?
That's right it's a kind of
textile, it's called cashmere.
Cashmere. So maybe you've
heard of cashmere wool.
It's a special kind of wool that comes from
animals. So this is a textile or a fabric
that is commonly used
to make pants nice pants
or suits for men.
Or scars or sweaters.
You've ever had a cashmere
sweater? You know it's very
luxurious, very soft.
So it can be a little bit
expensive depending on the quality and
that's what we're going to be looking at now.
We're going to be making
a suit out of cashmere.
So why don't we listen to
our dialogue for the first time.
Welcome to Bill's fabric world.
What can I do for you today?
I was wondering if you guys
also tailored
clothes? Sure we do.
We have the best tailors in the
country. What is it that you need exactly?
Well I'm looking to
get a custom made suit.
Excellent. We have
the finest cashmere
at affordable prices. How
about we get you measured?
Let's start off by measuring
the width of your shoulders.
Now let's measure the length of your
arms and this bit around your neck here.
Can you make sure you leave
a little extra space in the collar?
My neck gets easily irritated.
No problem. Now for your pants. Let
me just measure your waist and the inseam.
You might also want to
leave a little extra room
in the waist area. I tend
to gain a few pounds
over the holidays. Okay.
Now you can pick your
fabric and pattern
design. Please follow me.
So this reminds me of
something that people
used to do a lot more
often. So you go to the
tailor and you'd have
some clothes made.
Most people don't
do this anymore. Yeah.
Well it's actually really
interesting maybe because it's
more expensive nowadays
or tailors are harder to find.
That's right. So
let's learn about the
words first and what they
mean and then maybe we
can talk about this at
the end of today's show.
Language takeaway. All
right. So today on language
takeaway we have a word
that is a noun and a verb.
So as you mentioned the
person that makes suits is a tailor.
That's right. You can
say my uncle is a tailor.
He makes clothes
for famous people.
But this word is also a verb.
That means it's an action word.
We can say my uncle, the tailor, he tailors
clothes. Okay. So two tailor clothes
and what does it mean
when you say to tailor?
Well it can have two meanings. The first
is what we learn about in today's dialogue.
It means to make clothes. So to
make a shirt or to make a pair of pants.
But these days we often say to tailor, which
means to fix something. So for example,
Marco, if you buy a pair of pants and
they're too long, you can have them tailor.
Have them tailored and that means
that I am going to have them fixed.
So they fit me
properly. Exactly.
This is a lot more common
right now. Okay. So we're going
to be tailoring clothes.
Now if any of you have ever
been to the tailor, what
they do is they measure you.
And what do they measure? Well, in this
case, they get the width of your shoulders.
What's really great about
these upcoming words
is that they're useful in
math as well, math and
basic measurements. So width
is how big something is across.
Across how wide something is.
Exactly. Wide width.
Okay. So that's the width.
Now your shoulders,
they are wide and well,
your legs on the other
hand, your legs and arms.
You don't measure the width.
Usually you measure the length.
How long they are. Okay.
So width and length. Now
just to throw it in there.
This wasn't in the dialogue, but what
would be the other measure word?
So the third word
would be height.
So you think of a rectangle.
You have the width.
How wide something is. The
length. How long it is and the height.
How tall it is. How tall it is.
Right. So width, length,
and height. All right.
Now that we've measured our arms and legs,
now we want to measure our waist. Okay.
This is the important one.
This is also the sensitive one.
If you find that you've gained
some weight, we measure the waist.
Okay. That's how big you
are around your stomach.
And so usually we
measure this in a circle.
Okay. Okay. So you've
heard of a 26 inch
waist or a 32 inch waist. This
is the size of your stomach.
Okay. So it's just
above your hips, right?
As you say, it's your
stomach. And well, we've
measured the waist. And
now in men, especially,
they measure the inseam.
Now this is very particular
for tailors and
having suits made.
What is the inseam of your pants?
Well, think of the word in inside.
This is the inside
of your pants.
So from your foot to the middle of
your pants where your zipper starts.
Okay. So that's not
the outside length.
It's the inside
length. Okay. Uh-huh.
Now, for example, skirts,
they don't have inseams, right?
No, because there's no inside.
There's no middle, right?
So it's just like a circle. Okay.
But in pants or shorts,
you have an inseam.
That's where it's connected
in the middle. All right.
So also in shorts, very
interesting. So you can measure
the inseam of pants
or shorts. All right.
So very interesting in
particular words for tailors. Why
don't we listen to
our dialogue again?
And we'll be back shortly.
Welcome to Bill's fabric world.
What can I do for you
today? I was wondering if you
guys also tailor
clothes. Sure we do.
We have the best tailors in the
country. What is it that you need exactly?
Well, I'm looking to
get a custom made suit.
Excellent. We
have the finest cash
mirrors at affordable prices.
How about we get you measured?
Let's start off by
measuring the width
of your shoulders. Now,
let's measure the length
of your arms and this
bit around your neck here.
Can you make sure you leave
a little extra space in the collar?
My neck gets easily irritated.
No problem. Now for your
pants. Let me just measure
your waist and the
inseam. You might also want
to leave a little extra
room in the waist area.
I tend to gain a few pounds
over the holidays. Okay.
Now you can pick your
fabric and pattern design.
Please follow me.
All right. We're back.
So now we have three key phrases
that we found in this dialogue.
So let's take a
look at them now in
fluency builder. Fluency
builder. This first phrase
is the topic of today's
lesson. Well, we talked
a little bit about
measurements for a suit,
but in particular, we're getting a custom
made suits. Okay. So this word custom made.
Well, custom is important.
It means special or unique.
There's no other
like it. So we can talk
about custom cars. That
means a car that has been
fixed, especially for you.
Okay. So a custom made
suit would be a suit
that was made specifically
for your height, for
how big your waist is, etc.
Specifically for you.
Right. So a suit that I buy
at the department
store is just a normal suit,
but a suit that I have made
for me is a custom made suit.
Okay. And as you
say, you can use it
for cars, a custom made
car, or maybe for example,
a custom made
custom made kitchen.
That means that you get to
pick every single part of the
kitchen that you want.
Many people do that, right?
They have custom built
or custom made homes.
Yeah, that's that's always
something I've wanted
to do, but I hear that it's
much more expensive than
getting a normal
home made. All right.
So that's the first key phrase.
Now moving on, when we talk
about measuring, we say,
I measured, I measured the
length of this street,
right? Or let's measure you
so we can see how big
you are. But if you notice in
the dialogue, we
use the passive voice.
He says, let's get you measured.
Okay. I got measured or it got
measured to get measured as
you say is the is the passive voice.
Now what's the difference between passive
and active? All right. So basically what
happens here is we are
concentrating on the person
and the action falling
upon you, for example.
So I got measured. What
happened to me? I got measured.
Who did it? Who measured
you? We don't know.
We don't know. We
don't care. All right.
The point, the important
part is that you were measured.
You got measured. But
we could have a different
phrase. We say, for
example, I will measure this
table or he measures
the height of the door.
Mm-hmm. And we
know he measures. Right.
I will measure. We
know who the actor is.
That means it's active voice.
Because the focus is on who's
doing this action. But
in passive voice, the
important thing is who
is receiving the action.
Right. Now it's a little
bit complicated because
as you can see,
measured is in the past.
But we're not really
talking about the past.
So it may get a
little bit complicated.
We can take a more in-depth look
at that in the community section.
You can ask a couple questions.
We'll place a couple of
examples. But it's kind of hard to
get into the grammar over
an audio podcast. Right.
That's true. So that's
what we have the practice
space on the website.
All right. Now moving on,
we have our last phrase.
And when he was talking
about the waste and
how he should leave a
little bit of extra room,
it's because he tends,
he tends to gain a
few pounds. Okay.
So to gain a few pounds is like
gaining a kilo. It means to gain
weight over the holidays.
And in this case, to
tend to, I tend to means
I normally or I usually.
So for example, Marco, what
do you tend to eat for breakfast?
I tend to eat scrambled eggs and
a glass of yogurt. That's healthy. Do
you tend to run late in the morning? Yes.
True. All right. So
tend to its tendency is
what usually happens.
It's normal. It's normal.
All right. So very
interesting phrase is very
interesting words. Why
don't we listen to our dialogue
for the last time. Welcome to Bill's
Fabric World. What can I do for you today?
I was wondering if you
guys also tailored clothes?
Sure we do. We have the
best tailors in the country.
What is it that
you need? Exactly.
Well, I'm looking to get a
custom made suit. Excellent.
We have the finest cash
mirrors at affordable prices.
How about we get you measured?
Let's start off by measuring
the width of your shoulders.
Now let's measure the length of your
arms and this bit around your neck here.
Can you make sure you leave
a little extra space in the collar?
My neck gets easily irritated.
No problem. Now for your pants. Let
me just measure your waist and the inseam.
You might also want to
leave a little extra room
in the waist area. I tend
to gain a few pounds
over the holidays. Okay.
Now you can pick your
fabric and pattern
design. Please follow me.
All right. So we talked
earlier about how most
people buy their clothes
at a department store
or a clothing store. Have
you seen much of this?
You know, maybe back in
Ecuador. It's more common
than in America. Yeah,
usually people just go
to a department store
and get suits for example,
but it's actually very
common as well because
it's kind of in their
artisans to be like a shoe
maker or to be a tailor.
So actually people like
it more and go to tailors
because they kind of
become renowned. Like,
oh, he used to make suits
for the president. So,
you know, people really,
really like to get suits
made there. And obviously
they fit much better. You
feel more comfortable.
And you look better.
Yeah. As I've said before,
you know, I see people
who who buy all these suits.
My brother, for example,
they never quite fit right.
You can tell it's a little
too big in the shoulders.
My brother's tall.
So his pants are
always a little bit too short.
But when you come to a
place like China and
those people can get these
these suits made for them,
they just look fabulous.
It looks very, very nice. Yeah.
So maybe you guys can tell
us if you've ever had anything
tailor made not only
guys suits, but girls also
get tailor made dresses,
tailor made blouses.
I always get coats made
actually because my
shoulders are broad. And
so it's hard for me to find
coats that fit right. But
if I get one custom made,
it looks really good. Right. So
come to our website EnglishPod.
com, leave your questions
and comments there.
And we'll see you guys later.
Until next time guys. Bye. Bye.